# Sai Hemanth Beeraka

www.saihemanth.com

## CONTACT

+91 848287 47686

Chennai, India

in linkedin/saihemanthb

**y** twitter/saihemanth9019

github/shb9019

## **EDUCATION**

## NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, TRICHY

B. Tech in Computer Science Engineering Minor in Management MAY 2016 - MAY 2020 CGPA: 8.77/10

CGPA: 8.77/10 Tiruchirappalli, India

## **SKILLS**

#### Proficient

Java • JavaScript • SQL React • Spring Boot • Node Intermediate

C++ • Python • Solidity

PHP • Laravel

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- 5th TopCoder Humblefool Cup
- Winner EthIndia Hackathon '19
- Winner Pragyan Hackathon '17
- Candidate Master CodeForces

#### PROFILE

Competent and passionate Software Engineer with 1.5+ years of professional experience in building JavaScript and Java-based web applications. Consistently recognized as an impressive programmer who grasps ideas quickly and has brilliant problemsolving and debugging skills. This repertoire is complemented by an unquenchable curiosity to learn and apply novel technical concepts.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### D. E. SHAW INDIA | MEMBER TECHNICAL

Jul 2020 - Present | Hyderabad, India | deshawindia.com

- Engineered Spring-based solutions to store data from various internal HCM systems into a shared data warehouse.
- Developed a React website for the firm's leaders to visualize headcount and attrition trends enabling informed decisions.
- Delivered reporting solutions to help HC teams in New York and India manage and acquire talent across entities.
- Built generic GraphQL APIs that expose data from multiple HC sources for other teams to consume.

#### D. E. SHAW INDIA | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

May 2019 - Jul 2019 | Hyderabad, India | deshawindia.com

- Developed a full-stack web application to manage the bookings of the firm's multiple housing residences, which was achieved earlier by a more rudimentary and error-prone method.
- Used Java Spring Boot hosted on a Tomcat server for the backend and React-Redux for the frontend.

#### **GMETRI STUDIO** | WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

Nov 2017 – Jan 2018 | Bangalore, India | gmetri.com

- Improvised and added functionalities to multiple VR products of clients built using ReactVR and ThreeJS.
- Worked on the company dashboard's APIs, which assisted collaboration across multiple teams.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### CODE CHARACTER | Jan - Mar 2018 & Jan - Mar 2019

github.com/delta/codecharacter-web

An Al programming challenge where players, using a high-level API, write code to control troops and battle opponents in a real-time strategy game simulation.

- 10,000+ matches by 1,300+ players from over 70 countries.
- Collaborated on the C++ simulator responsible for processing player code and simulating the game.
- Built the web app, which handles user registrations, code submissions, and renders simulations received from the back-end.
- Handled the dockerizing and deployment of different components of the project.

## NIT TRICHY WEBSITE | JUN 2019 - JUN 2020

nitt.edu

• Responsible for maintaining and updating the college website built on PHP with the help of 20 juniors, as part of the college WebTeam.